Inventory of the Thomas H. Binford papers, 1940-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Thomas H. Binford papers, 1940-1967
74033
Binford, Thomas H., 1896-1973
1 manuscript box, 2 oversize boxes, 4 envelopes (1.6 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Contains materials related to the Java Sea campaign and other Pacific campaigns during World War II, Japanese war criminals, and American attempts to prevent hostilities between China and Taiwan, including documentation such as addresses, reports, awards, printed matter, and photographs.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1974.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
A Vice Admiral in the United States Navy, Binford was the commanding officer of Destroyer Division 58 from 1941 to 1942, serving in the United States Asiatic Fleet in the Java Sea. He was in command during the Battle of Badoeng Straits, off the Island of Bali, in 1942, for which he was presented the Navy Cross.
Scope and Content of Collection
Contains materials related to the Java Sea campaign and other Pacific campaigns during World War II, Japanese war criminals, and American attempts to prevent hostilities between China and Taiwan, including documentation such as addresses, reports, awards, printed matter, and photographs.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
United States. Navy. Destroyer Division 58.; United States. Navy--Officers.; War crime trials--Japan.; World War, 1939-1945--Campaigns--Pacific Ocean.; World War, 1939-1945--Naval operations.; Taiwan--Foreign relations--United States.; United States--Foreign relations--Taiwan.; Yokohama Trials, 1945-1949.
Collection Contents
- Personal file, 1940-1967
  - Personal file (Folder 1: 1-4)
  - Orders (Folder 1: 5)
  - Awards and citations (Folder 1: 6)
  - Navy correspondence (Folder 1: 7)
  - Speeches and writings (Folder 1: 8)
  - Declassified materials (Folder 1: 9)
  - Miscellany (Folder 1: 10)
  - News clippings (Folder 1: 11)
  - Printed matter (Folder 1: 12-13)
- Photograph Albums, circa 1945-1954
  - 24 photos of Vice Admiral Binford's naval career, news clippings, and memorabilia, including 3 prints of Madame and Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek, 1 print of General Douglas MacArthur, and 1 print of Japanese Defense Minister Tojo, circa 1945 (Folder 2)
  - 80 photos of Vice Admiral Binford's naval career, including news clippings, memorabilia, and photos of General Omar Bradley, 1950-1954 (Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1940-1954
  - 70 photos of awards and presentations to Admiral Binford, including several photos of Admiral Binford with Eleanor Roosevelt, 1940-1954 (Folder A-B)
  - 36 photos of Vice Admiral Binford's tour of Formosa, 1940-1950, including 27 prints of persons of high military and civilian significance and 10 photos of combat action off Okinawa, 1945 (Folder C)
  - 1 photo of Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Air, Artemus L. Gates, presenting the Legion of Merit and Silver Star to Admiral Binford, October 26, 1944 (Folder mD)